Guide to the Victor Rabinowitz Papers TAM.123
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Victor Rabinowitz Papers
1918-2003
1955-1980
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Rabinowitz, Victor
TAM.123
34 Linear Feet in 35 boxes in 1 folder in a shared oversize box.
Victor Rabinowitz (1911- 2007) had a long and distinguished career as an attorney specializing in civil liberties cases, international law, labor law and U.S. constitutional law. He was a partner in the firm of Rabinowitz, Boudin, Standard and Krinsky and argued cases at many levels in New York City and New York, as well as appearing before the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia and the U. S. Supreme Court. Rabinowitz represented Alger Hiss in his efforts to obtain government documents relevant to re-opening his case. He also represented the governments of Cuba and Chile in U.S. courts, and appeared on behalf on many labor unions and leftist individuals and political organizations. He was an activist in the American Labor Party in the 1940s and was a candidate for office on the ALP ticket. The collection contains correspondence, appointment books, writings (including drafts of his 1996 memoir Unrepentant Leftist: A Lawyer's Memoir), political papers, legal records, and FOIA files. It also includes administrative files of the Louis M. Rabinowitz Foundation.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers were purchased from Victor Rabinowitz in April 2004. A small number of additional materials were added to the collection in 2006. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2004.027, 2004.028, and NPA 2006 044.
Arrangement
Series I is arranged chronologically; all other series are arranged alphabetically.
The files are organized into 5 series:
Series I: Correspondence, 1944-2002
Series II: Subject Files, 1929-2003
Series III: Case Files, 1918-2001
Series IV: Appointment Books, 1943-2001
Series V: Records of the Louis M. Rabinowitz Foundation, 1957-1991
Series I is arranged chronologically; all other series are arranged alphabetically.
The files are organized into 5 series:
Missing Title
I, Correspondence, 1944-2002.
II, Subject Files, 1929-2003.
III, Case Files, 1918-2001.
IV, Appointment Books, 1943-2001.
V, Records of the Louis M. Rabinowitz Foundation, 1957-1991.
Historical/Biographical Note
Victor Rabinowitz was the son of Jewish immigrants, born into a family where radical politics was common. His maternal grandfather was an anarchist and Yiddish-language author under the pseudonym Joseph Netter. Rabinowitz's father was a successful manufacturer in the clothing industry who in 1944 established the Louis M. Rabinowitz foundation, and which supported projects in Jewish scholarship and culture and a variety of progressive causes. The Foundation was administered by Victor after his father's death in 1957.
After receiving his law degree from the University of Michigan in 1934 and joining a law firm, Rabinowitz became involved in the work of the International Labor Defense, a Popular Front organization. He joined the National Lawyers Guild, a politically left professional organization, upon its founding in 1938, and the same year joined the progressive law firm of Louis Boudin. There he met Leonard Boudin, Louis' nephew, who would become his law partner and close friend for the next fifty years. The firm's practice centered upon labor law, which was to become a focal point of Victor's legal work for the next two decades. His political views coincided with those of the Communist Party, of which he was to be a member from 1942-1960. In 1947, the law firm that eventually came to be known as Rabinowitz, Boudin (Leonard), Standard and Krinsky was formed. With the coming of the Cold War and its attendant anti-Communist legislation and government investigations, Rabinowitz's practice increasingly involved defending unions accused of being led by Communists, notably the American Communications Association; individual Communists, including Steve Nelson; New York City public school teachers dismissed for refusing to answer questions about their political affiliations; and the Communist Party itself, as well as progressive union dissidents in such formerly radical unions as the National Maritime Union. He was active in the Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, a left-wing offshoot of the American Civil Liberties Union. Rabinowitz was an activist in the American Labor Party in the 1940s; he was a candidate on the ALP ticket for County Court Judge of Kings County, NY (1942) and for Congress (1947).
Victor Rabinowitz's post-1960 clients included the government of Cuba and the socialist government of Chile (1970-73) pursuing cases in U.S. courts, alleged Soviet spy Alger Hiss during the 1970s in an unsuccessful attempt to obtain documents relating to his case from the FBI, various labor unions and union rank-and-file activists, civil rights activists and individuals arrested while protesting the Vietnam War. He also defended his daughter Joni Rabinowitz on perjury charges connected with her work for the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, and his son Peter J. Rabinowitz, a college professor allegedly transferred from Southwest College, a public junior college in Chicago, for his political activities. Rabinowitz also served two terms as president of the National Lawyers Guild, beginning in 1967, and was active in the Bill of Rights Foundation and the Fund for Education and Legal Defense. Other clients included the Freedom Socialist Party, the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, and Otto Nathan, executor of the estate of Albert Einstein. In 1996, Rabinowitz published an autobiography, Unrepentant Leftist: A Lawyer's Memoir. He died at his home in New York City, at the age of 96, in November 2007.
Sources:
Rabinowitz, Victor. Unrepentant Leftist: A Lawyer's Memoir. Urbana: University of Illinois Press, 1996.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Rabinowitz, Boudin, Standard and Krinsky: Legal Files (TAM 287)
National Lawyers Guild Records (TAM 191)
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains correspondence, appointment books, writings (including drafts of his memoir Unrepentant Leftist: A Lawyer's Memoir), political papers, and legal records and FOIA files. It also includes administrative files of the Louis M. Rabinowitz Foundation.
The correspondence series, arranged chronologically, focuses on Rabinowitz's political and legal activities, although there is some more personal material, including letters regarding his travels to Cuba and elsewhere. The subject files series includes files on a variety of individual, organizations, and activities, an oral history interview, and drafts of Unrepentant Leftist. The largest number of files relate to the National Lawyers Guild and include FOIA files on the Guild; and there is also a substantial number of files on the Emergency Civil Liberties Committee and the Fund for Education and Legal Defense. Other FOIA files concern Rabinowitz, Kathy Boudin, Leonard Boudin, Daniel Ellsberg, James Hoffa, and the Teachers' Union of the City of New York. Other individuals of note represented in this series include Frederick Vanderbilt Field, and authors Cedric Belfrage and his daughter Sally Belfrage. The subject files also include a small number of photographs of Victor Rabinowitz and his family, friends and clients (including Fidel Castro and Pete Seeger). Notable and/or extensive files in the Legal Case Files series include those on the American Communications Association, Alger Hiss, Peter Rabinowitz, the Freedom Socialist Party, and the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee. Other notable clients and cases included Harry Adler and Minerva Feinstein (v. NYC Board of Education – back pay), Kathy Boudin (murder), Carl and Anne Braden (sedition), Louis C. Fraina (aka Lewis Corey, draft resistance, 1918), Communist leader Irving Potash (subversive activities), and Anna Louise Strong (passport application). The Louis M. Rabinowitz Foundation records series includes correspondence, files relating to funding proposals accepted or rejected, and minutes.
College teachers |x Legal status, laws, etc |z United States |v Cases.; New York (N.Y.).; Reports.; Communist trials -- United States.; Communism -- United States.; Photographs.; Communists -- United States.; Lawyers -- Political activity -- United States.; Labor unions and communism -- United States.; Manuscripts; Legal files.; Correspondence.; Federal government records.; Labor union democracy |z United States.; Appointment books.; American Communications Association; American Labor Party; Rabinowitz, Peter J., 1944-; Strong, Anna Louise, 1885-1970; Bill of Rights Foundation; Boudin, Leonard, 1912-1989; Emergency Civil Liberties Committee; Hiss, Alger; Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (U.S.); Teachers' Union of the City of New York; National Maritime Union of America; National Lawyers Guild; Louis M. Rabinowitz Foundation; Fund for Education and Legal Defense; Freedom Socialist Party (U.S.); Hoffa, James R. (James Riddle), 1913-; Field, Frederick V. (Frederick Vanderbilt), 1905-2000; Feinstein, Minerva; Corey, Lewis; Ellsberg, Daniel.; Braden, Anne, 1924-2006; Braden, Carl, 1914-1975; Boudin, Kathy; Belfrage, Cedric, 1904-1990.; Belfrage, Sally, 1936-; Rabinowitz, Louis M.; Rabinowitz, Victor; Nathan, Otto, 1893-1987; Potash, Irving; Nelson, Steve, 1903-1993
- Series I: Correspondence, 1944-2002.
  - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1958, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 2000-2002 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Series II: Subject Files, 1929-2003.
  - Academic Freedom Cases: Applications for Reinstatement, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Academic Freedom Project (Brooklyn College): H. Foner, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Admission to Practice: VR, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - American Communications Association (ACA): Research, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - American Labor Party (ALP), 1947, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - ALP: Certificates, Minutes, etc., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - ALP: Election Forms and Legal Proceedings, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - ALP: Memo on Contested Elections, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - ALP: State Legislative Program, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - ALP: Victor Rabinowitz Congressional Campaign, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - ALP: Victor Rabinowitz State Senate Campaign, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - American Society of International Law, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Anhalt, Diana Z., 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Attorney Registration: VR, 1994-2003 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Behrstock, Julian: The Eighth Case, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Belfrage, Cedric, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Belfrage, Sally, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Belfrage, Sally: Letter to Alger and Isabel Hiss, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Berrigan, Daniel and Philip: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) File, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Bill of Rights Foundation (BORF), 1971-1979 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - BORF: "Nuclear Project", 1979 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Biographical, 1947-1992 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Book Research: General, 1952-1993 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Boudin, Kathy: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) File, 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Boudin, Leonard: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) File (I), 1961-1973 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Boudin, Leonard: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) File (II), 1961-1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Boudin, Leonard: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) File (III), 1961-1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Boudin, Leonard: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) File (IV), 1961-1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Boudin, Leonard: Memorial, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Boudin, Louis B.: Articles, 1929-1940 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Boudin, Louis B.: Articles, 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Braden, Carl, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Brown, Sarah Hart: Dissertation on Southern Liberalism, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Browning, Joan C., 1998 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Cases: Index, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Civil Rights: Albany, GA Cases, 1963-1973 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Civil Rights Congress (CRC), 1951 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Clippings and Articles, 1951, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Clippings and Articles: Political Affairs, 1990-1999 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Clippings: Re: Victor Rabinowitz, 1967-1972 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Cohn, Roy, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 16a)
  - Cold War Conference (University of Toledo), 1996 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Communist Control Act of 1954 (Box 4, Folder 17a)
  - Communist Party USA v. Subversive Activities Control Board, 1952-1991 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Communist Subversion of Summer Camps: Inquiry, 1918-1003, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Conference: "Anticommunism and the US" (Harvard), 1988-11 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Consolidated Laws of New York, Annotated: "Article 2: Party Organization", 1922, 1944-1948 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Consolidated Laws of New York, Annotated: "Article 6: Designation and Nomination of Candidates", 1922, 1944-1948 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Council of Federated Organizations (COFO): Henry Aronson Resignation, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Cuba, 1961, 1997, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Days, Drew, III, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - East Hampton Star: Helen Rattray, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Ellsberg, Daniel: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) File, 1971-1974 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee (ECLC), undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - ECLC, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - ECLC, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - ECLC, 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - ECLC (I), 1955 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - ECLC (II), 1955 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - ECLC (III), 1955 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - ECLC (IV), 1955 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - ECLC (I), 1956 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - ECLC (II), 1956 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - ECLC (I), 1957 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - ECLC (II), 1957 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - ECLC (III), 1957 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - ECLC, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - ECLC: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) File, 1955-1956, 1969-1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - ECLC: "You and the FBI" Advertisement, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - England: Victor Rabinowitz Trip, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Family (Photographs), 1970s, undated (Box 6, Folder 5A)
  - Field, Frederick Vanderbilt, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Foner, Henry: "Saul Mills and the Greater New York Industrial Union Council," Labor History, Vol. 31, no. 3, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Freedom of Information Requests: Correspondence, 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Fund for Education and Legal Defense, Inc. (FELD), 1965 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - FELD: Certificate of Incorporation, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - FELD: Correspondence, 1965-1969, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - FELD: Disbursements, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - FELD: Minutes, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - FELD: Payroll and Taxes, 1965-1971 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - FELD: Scholarships, 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Ginger, Ann Fagan, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Ginger, Ann Fagan: "The Energizing Effect of Enforcing a Human Rights Treaty," DePaul Law Review, Vol. 42, no. 4, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Grossman, Victor (aka Stephen Wechsler), 1990 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Hoffa, James: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) File, 1976-1977-1977 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Hogan, Lenore Bredeson: Interview with Victor Rabinowitz, 1979-11 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities (HUAC): General, 1949-1958, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Inter-Office Memos, 1989, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - International Association of Democratic Lawyers, 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - International Association of Democratic Lawyers, 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - International Trade Union and Legal Commission, 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Jagan, Cheddi, 1988, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Kachelmyer, Kim, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Kairys, David: Writings, 1984, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Kennedy, Eleanore, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Kliever, Marney, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Labor Union Investigations, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Law Class Reunion, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Liberal Citizens of Massachusetts, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Meiklejohn Civil Liberties Institute, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Michigan State Police: File on Victor Rabinowitz, 1967-1970 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Mitford, Jessica, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Namibia: Legal Study, 1981-1984 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - National Lawyers Guild (NLG), 1951, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - NLG, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - NLG, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - NLG, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - NLG, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - NLG, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - NLG, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - NLG, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - NLG, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - NLG, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - NLG, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - NLG, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - NLG, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - NLG, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - NLG, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - NLG, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - NLG, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - NLG, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - NLG: Anniversary Committee (50th), 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - NLG: Anniversary Dinner (50th), 1987 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - NLG: Anniversary Dinner (40th), 1977 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - NLG: Anniversary Film Proposal (50th), 1987 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - NLG: Anniversary Publications (50th), 1986 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - NLG: Board Meeting, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - NLG: Committee to Assist Southern Lawyers (CASL), 1962-1964 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - NLG: Committees of Correspondence, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - NLG: Constitutional Liberties Committee, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - NLG: Constitutional Liberties Committee, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - NLG: Convention (I), 1968 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - NLG: Convention (II), 1968 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - NLG: Convention: Constitution and Proposed Amendments, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - NLG: Convention: Minutes, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - NLG: Convention: Reports, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - NLG: Convention: Resolutions, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - NLG: Convention, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - NLG: Convention, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - NLG: Convention, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - NLG: Convention, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - NLG: Convention, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - NLG: Convention, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - NLG: Convention, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - NLG: Correspondence, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - NLG: Correspondence: National Office (I), 1968 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - NLG: Correspondence: National Office (II), 1968 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - NLG: Correspondence: National Office (III), 1968 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - NLG: Cuba Subcommittee, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - NLG: Eleanor Roosevelt, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - NLG: Finances/Restructuring, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - NLG: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) File (FBI), 1942-1948 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - NLG: FOIA File (FBI), 1949 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - NLG: FOIA File (FBI), 1950-1952 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - NLG: FOIA File (FBI), 1953 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - NLG: FOIA File (FBI), 1954-1956 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - NLG: FOIA File (FBI), 1957-1960 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - NLG: FOIA File (FBI), 1961-1964, 1967-1970 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - NLG: FOIA File (FBI), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - NLG: Foundation, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - NLG: Foundation, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - NLG: Foundation, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - NLG: Foundation, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - NLG: Foundation, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - NLG: Foundation, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - NLG: Foundation, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - NLG: Foundation, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - NLG: Foundation, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - NLG: Group Portrait (Oversize), undated (Box Shared Tamiment OS008, Folder 1)
  - National Lawyers Guild Foundation: Guild Notes, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - NLG: History, General, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - NLG: History, General, 1936-1986 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - NLG: International Association of Democratic Lawyers, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - NLG: International Association of Democratic Lawyers, 1989-1993 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - NLG: Judicial Project, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - NLG: Labor Project, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - NLG: Loan, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - NLG: Marxism and the Law Subcommittee, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - NLG: National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - NLG: Paul Zuber, FBI Informant, 1961-1963, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - NLG: Staff/Management Relations, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - NLG: Staff/Management Relations, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - NLG v. Attorney General: Settlement Discussions, 1978-1988 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Nelson, Steve: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) File (FBI), undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "Nothing but a Man" Company, 1963-1966, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - O'Dwyer, William, 1945, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Oral History: VR Interviewed by Norman Silber (Columbia), 1989 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Oral History: VR Interviewed by Norman Silber (Columbia): Correspondence, 1989-2001 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Photographs: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 10, Folder 5A)
  - Pomerance, Eve, 1995-1998 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Popper, Martin: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) File (FBI), 1955 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Portraits (Includes Pete Seeger and Haywood Burns), undated (Box 10, Folder 7A)
  - Portugal, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Progressive Labor Party: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) File (FBI), 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Rabinowitz, Joni (formerly Joan), 1963-1966, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Rabinowitz, Louis M., 1957 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Rabinowitz, Louis M.: Oral History, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Rabinowitz, Peter, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Rabinowitz, Victor: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) File (FBI) (I), undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Rabinowitz, Victor: FOIA File (FBI) (II), undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Rabinowitz, Victor: FOIA File (FBI) (III), undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Rabinowitz, Victor: FOIA File (FBI) (IV), undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Rabinowitz, Victor: FOIA File (FBI) (V), undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Rabinowitz, Victor: FOIA File (FBI) (VI), undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Rabinowitz, Victor: FOIA File (FBI) (VII), undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Rabinowitz, Victor: FOIA File (FBI) (VIII), undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Rabinowitz, Victor: FOIA File (FBI) (IX), undated (Box 11, Folder 2)